Peter Maximilian Fortunato

Contact

- peter@solplots.com
- solplots.com
- LinkedIn
- GitHub

Summary

Peter is a data scientist with over three years of professional experience and is currently a member of the Strategic Routing team at Worldpay (formerly part of FIS). He is an expert in the R and SQL programming languages as well as analytical storytelling.

Skills

- Languages: R, SQL, Python
- Tools: Databricks, RStudio, Quarto, Git, Snowflake, Jupyter, Streetlight, ArcGIS,
- Libraries: tidyverse (ggplot2, dplyr, etc.), Shiny, RMarkdown

Experience

Data Scientist I, Strategic Routing — Worldpay, Inc

Remote | Dec 2023 - Present

- Implements network routing product to maximize merchant cost savings on card processing fees
- Performs ad-hoc analyses simulating potential merchant savings using a "least cost routing" method

- Engineers routing table update processes by integrating various documents and requests
- Monitors product performance to match negotiated transaction volumes from network deals

Data Scientist, Transit & Rail Planning — Vanasse Hangen Brustlin, Inc. (VHB)

Washington, D.C. | Sept 2022 - Dec 2023

- Analyzed General Transit Feed Specification (GTFS) data in conjunction with Automated Passenger Count data to program R scripts and output load factor and schedule adherence KPI for transit studies
- Developed and maintains a suite of transit planning and origin/destination traffic analysis Shiny Apps known as Data Trippers that resulted in assisting clients' decision making processes

Data Scientist — Ohio Kentucky Indiana Regional Council of Governments (OKI)

Cincinnati, Ohio | May 2021 - Aug 2022

- Repurposed open-source R scripts to develop inaugural method evaluating roadway safety performance in the 8-county OKI region which resulted in the Excess Expected Crashes (EEC) KPI
- Presented methodology at area analytics conferences and the useR! Conference 2022 (recognized)
- Visualized of existing conditions and commodity flow using Freight Analysis Framework (FAF)

Education

M.S. in Business Analytics Miami University of Ohio, 2021

B.A. in International Studies Miami University of Ohio, 2020

Projects

- Safety Performance Evaluation of OKI's Regional Highway Network: As part of my work in developing a process to evaluate roadway safety while working for OKI, I organized my research into a poster presentation and submitted it to the useR! 2022 Conference. The poster was recognized as one of five "best of the conference". View PDF Report
- Mediterranean Corridor Volunteer Work: Supported Commissioner Josep Vicent Boira Maiques of Valencia, Spain to develop visualizations that examined existing rail infrastructures related to type of service and technical characteristics.
 Certification Letter (in Spanish)